### **JOSHUA MORGAN**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB Linkedin | GitHub

Greenville, SC 29650 864-404-1515 joshuamorgan0605@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I am a **full stack developer** specializing in **React, Node.js (Express.js), MongoDB**, and **Jest**. My current interests include **Next.js, TypeScript, Cypress.io, React Testing Library**, and **Storybook**. I have **3 years** of experience in the JavaScript ecosystem. And I have built and worked on web applications geared toward the general public and general industry.

# **Projects**

In-Season Produce Project ( <u>Code I View Site</u> )

May 2023 - November 2023

A full stack **Node.js** (**Express**), **React** application for the person seeking to find in-season local produce.

- Developed RESTful API to control user functions using Express.js with MongoDB as a persistence layer while utilizing React on the frontend.
- Incorporated **React Router v6** for client-side routing, providing faster user experiences.
- Managed remote data w/ **React Query** simplifying data fetching, caching, and synchronization.
- Enforced secure data transfer protocols and encryption mechanisms and ensured user data remained protected via **JWT Tokens** and **HTTP Cookies.**

React Job Simulator ( Code | View Site )

**December 2023 - March 2024** 

Took part in job simulation program designed by Sr. React developed. Worked on error logging and monitoring tool built with **Next.js** framework, **React**, and **TypeScript**.

- Completed feature requests from Kanban board simulating professional work environment.
- Utilized Storybook, providing documentation of components and visual testing in isolation.
- Wrote automated tests with Cypress, improving proper project design and function.
- Built UI kit based on Figma designs, creating pixel-perfect rendering.

# **Experience**

#### **Spartanburg Day School**

2013 - 2016

Upper School VISTAS Teacher – Spartanburg, SC

• Supported learning disabled students (ADHD, Aspergers, Dyslexia, etc) in acquiring and applying the skills and know-how to succeed in a college-preparatory classroom, improving letter grades and confidence.

Hanalani Schools 2010 – 2011

**Upper School Instructor** — Mililani Town, HI

• Built 10th grade English curriculum that conveyed core content while also inspiring collaboration, adaptive problem-solving skills, critical thinking, communication, and positive digital citizenship.

#### **Evangelical Christian School**

2007 - 2009

**Upper School Instructor** — Fort Myers, FL

- Tailored Theology curriculum, giving students a personal and appropriate learning experience.
- Develop curriculum for Keyboarding class, leaving students with a comprehensive and interactive course.

#### **Education**

Full Stack Software Engineering
Launch School (Link)
Elementary Teacher Certification
USC Upstate — Spartanburg, SC
Masters of Arts in Teaching
Bob Jones University – Greenville, SC

June 2020 - Feb 2023

Aug 2011 — May 2012

Aug 2004 - May 2007